(
"ai_sub_version": "2.8.1",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"ollama_search": (
"key": "**********"
),
"web_search_tool": "ollama",
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
Otonose Kanade IN PROGRESS BIRTHDAY LIVE 2026
[Title: Otonose Kanade IN PROGRESS BIRTHDAY LIVE 2026]
目を開けて 口ずさむ 輝ける
Open your eyes, hum a tune, you'll shine
“きっと 無敵になる”
"Surely I'll become invincible"
Feel my heart
See me become the GREATEST
No one can beat me
Cuz I'm a GREATEST
固く結び直した靴紐が 羽に見えてどこまででも跳べる
The shoelaces I tied tightly again look like wings,
予感がする
I have a feeling I can jump anywhere
追いかけるなんて趣味じゃない
I'm not into chasing
追い越そう 明日だって
Let's overtake, tomorrow
夢のまんま終わるほど眠くないわ
isn't sleepy enough to end as a dream
そう 何もかも大丈夫
Yes, everything will be alright
奇跡よりも大胆に勝つの
I'll win more boldly than a miracle
見たことない景色だって 光に満ちていく
Even scenery I've never seen will be filled with light
Wanna be the GREATEST
地図ならばこの胸に 迸る熱がある
If it's a map, there's a gushing heat in this chest
誰も止めらんないmy way
No one can stop my way
Wanna be the GREATEST
弱音も重ねればシンフォニー
Even weak words become a symphony if layered
強くなれる 歌って
You can become strong, sing
(Feel my heart)
“きっと 無敵になる”
"Surely I'll become invincible"
(Feel my light)
部屋で一人 描いたステージも
Remember the stage I drew alone in my room,
覚えていて 居場所になる
it becomes a place where I belong
声が聞こえてくる
I can hear the voice
深呼吸をして飛び乗るぐらいが正攻法だって
Taking a deep breath and jumping on is the best method,
胸を張って踊るのも悪くないわ
dancing with my chest out is not bad either
恐れないで 大丈夫
Don't be afraid, it's alright
唱えるたび「絶対」になるの
Every time you chant it, it becomes "absolute"
一度きりの人生だって この手で舵を取れ
Even if it's a life only once, take the helm with these hands
Wanna be the GREATEST
私が私として輝ける 道を行く
I go on the path where I can shine as myself
声もきらめいてmy day
My voice also sparkles, my day
Wanna be the GREATEST
目覚めを奏でてオーバーチュア
Play the overture to awaken
望むほどに叶って
It comes true as much as I wish
(Feel my heart)
もっと素敵になる
It becomes more wonderful
(Feel my light)
Feel my heart
See me become the GREATEST
No one can beat me
Cuz I'm a GREATEST
Wanna be the GREATEST
諦めた「好き」の数 上を向く理由がある
There's a reason to look up for the number of "likes" I gave up on
涙 導いてmy beat
Tears, guide my beat
Wanna be the GREATEST
傷跡も連れてアレグロ
Bring the scars too, allegro
強くなれる 歌って
You can become strong, sing
(Feel my heart)
もっと光差す方へ
Towards the side where more light shines
(Feel my light)
(Feel my heart)
“きっと 無敵になる”
"Surely I'll become invincible"
(Feel my light)
音乃瀬奏 IN PROGRESS BIRTHDAY LIVE 2026
[Title: Otonose Kanade IN PROGRESS BIRTHDAY LIVE 2026]
飛行艇 | 作詞・作曲：常田大希
[Song: Hikoutei | Lyrics & Composition: Daiki Tsuneta]
どんな夢を見に行こうか
What kind of dreams should we go see?
正しさばかりに恐れ戦かないで
Don't be afraid and tremble only at correctness
自由自在に飛び回って
Fly around freely
ステップ・バイ・ステップ
Step by step
ビートを刻んで
Beat by beat
果ての無いパーティーを続けようか
Shall we continue the endless party?
この時代に飛び乗って
Jump onto this era
今夜この街を飛び立って
Tonight, fly away from this city
大空を飛び回って
Fly around the big sky
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
この風に飛び乗って
Jump onto this wind
今夜台風の目となって
Tonight, become the eye of the typhoon
大空を飛び回って
Fly around the big sky
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
代わり映えしない日常の片隅で
In the corner of this unchanging daily life
無邪気に笑っていられたらいいよな
It would be nice to be able to laugh innocently
無意味な旅を続けたって
Continue this meaningless journey
ワン・バイ・ワン
One by one
一歩ずつでいいさ
One step at a time is fine
歓声も罵声も呑み込んで
Swallow both cheers and boos
この時代に飛び乗って
Jump onto this era
今夜愚かな杭となって
Tonight, become the foolish stake
過ちを恐れないで
Don't be afraid of mistakes
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
この風に飛び乗って
Jump onto this wind
今夜名も無き風となって
Tonight, become the nameless wind
清濁を併せ呑んで
Swallow both the pure and the impure
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
大雨降らせ
Make the heavy rain fall
大地震わせ
Make the earth tremble
過去を祝え
Celebrate the past
明日を担え
Carry tomorrow
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
大雨降らせ
Make the heavy rain fall
大地震わせ
Make the earth tremble
過去を祝え
Celebrate the past
明日を担え
Carry tomorrow
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
大雨降らせ
Make the heavy rain fall
大地震わせ
Make the earth tremble
過去を祝え
Celebrate the past
明日を担え
Carry tomorrow
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
大雨降らせ
Make the heavy rain fall
大地震わせ
Make the earth tremble
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
この時代に飛び乗って
Jump onto this era
今夜この街を飛び立って
Tonight, fly away from this city
大空を飛び回って
Fly around the big sky
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
この風に飛び乗って
Jump onto this wind
今夜台風の目となって
Tonight, become the eye of the typhoon
大空を飛び回って
Fly around the big sky
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
貴女の期待に飛び乗って
Jump onto your expectations
今夜この羽根で飛びたくて
Tonight, I want to fly with these wings
この大空を飛びたくて
I want to fly in this big sky
命生まれ 命生まれ
Life is born, life is born
この風に飛び乗って
Jump onto this wind
今夜名も無き風となって
Tonight, become the nameless wind
清濁を併せ呑んで
Swallow both the pure and the impure
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
ヴィーナス
[Song: Venus]
泡に乗って海を越え
Riding on the bubbles to cross the sea
季節をまた連れてくる
Bringing the season again
貝殻に耳澄ます
Listening to the seashells
静寂にも声を探す
Looking for a voice even in silence
教えておくれ
Please tell me
この風はどこから吹いているの
Where is this wind blowing from?
そこにいるの
Are you there?
時間よ どうか待って
Time, please wait
僕だけが祈っている
I am the only one praying
産まれる前に 出会っていたよう
It feels like we had met before we were born
寄せては返す 足跡も消して
The waves come and go, erasing even footprints
近づくほどに 遠ざかるあなた
The closer I get, the further you move away
ヴィーナス 風にしたためた詩
Venus, a poem written in the wind
摘まれる花になりたい 物言わぬ貝でありたい
I want to be a flower to be picked,
I want to be a silent seashell
待っている わかっている
Waiting, I know
絶やさぬ人になりたい 底知れぬ愛を知りたい
I want to be someone who doesn't let it fade,
I want to know bottomless love
待っている 縋っている
Waiting, clinging
雨なく花は咲かない 泣かずに憂いは枯れない
Without rain, flowers won't bloom;
without crying, worries won't wither
去っていく 辿っていく
Going away, tracing
あなたが誰か知らないのに探さずにいられない
I don't know who you are,
but I can't help searching for you
去っていく 拾っていく欠片
Going away, picking up the fragments
夢に明け暮れ 寝息も秤にかけたまま
Spending days in dreams,
leaving even my sleeping breath on the scale
おいてゆくの
Will you leave it behind?
忘れるよう願って
Hoping to forget
幸せを祈っている
I am praying for your happiness
眠れるように 握っては目覚め
As if sleeping, I grasp it and wake up
大人になれば ざわめきも消えて
Once I become an adult, the noise disappears
息づくほどに 遠のいてゆくもの
Things that move further away as I breathe
ヴィーナス いつか思い出す
Venus, I will remember it someday
産まれる前に 出会っていたよう
It feels like we had met before we were born
寄せては返す 足跡も消して
The waves come and go, erasing even footprints
近づくほどに 遠ざかるあなた
The closer I get, the further you move away
ヴィーナス 風にしたためた詩
Venus, a poem written in the wind
背が伸びた頃 ねえ きっと会いましょう
When I grew taller, hey, let's meet for sure
砂に埋めた 涙も還して
Returning even the tears buried in the sand
生まれ変われど もう一度あなたの
Even if I am reborn, once again, your...
ヴィーナス 微笑みと生きていたい
Venus, I want to live with a smile
ヴィーナス 巡る あたたかな音
Venus, the warm sound that circles around
はい！ということで始まりました！
Yes! And so it has begun!
音乃瀬奏生誕祭2026！見に来てくれてありがとうございます！
Otonose Kanade's Birthday Festival 2026!
Thank you for coming to watch!
ふぅー！
Phew!
ちょっと駆け足でね、2曲お届けしましたが いかがでしたでしょうか？
I've delivered two songs in a bit of a rush,
but how did you like them?
たくさん、コメント、パチパチありがとう！
Thank you for all the comments and the applause!
見えてるよ、ありがとう！
I can see you, thank you!
はい、そしてね、ハッシュタグ、えーこちら、画面にも出ているんですが
Also, the hashtag... which is shown on the screen here...
#音乃瀬奏生誕祭2026 でいっぱいポストしてください！
Please post lots using #OtonoseKanadeBirthdayFestival2026!
ちょっとこの配信が終わったらエゴサーチをするなり
Once this stream ends, I'll be searching for my name and such...
いっぱい見に行くので感想とかここが良かったよとか呟いてくれたらとっても嬉しいです！
I'll go look at them a lot, so I'd be very happy if you'd
tweet your thoughts or what you liked!
ハッピーバースデーありがとう！
Thank you for the "Happy Birthday"!
こちらの配信ですね、あのタイトル、ライブのタイトル
This stream... that title, the live's title...
「IN PROGRESS」というタイトルになっています。
Is titled "IN PROGRESS."
どういう意味かなーってお前らがいっぱい推測してくれたと思いますが
I'm sure you all speculated a lot about what it means...
大体合ってました、すごい！
And you were mostly right, amazing!
こちらのタイトルですね、こちらの英語には「未完成」という...
This title... this English phrase carries the meaning of "incomplete"...
...意味が含まれていまして
...and that meaning is included,
奏の、未完成ながら進むというスタンスを
I hope to show you Kanade's current stance,
このライブでお見せできればなと思います
of moving forward even while incomplete.
はい、ちょっとまだ自分に
Yes. I'm still...
完全に満足しきっていないけど
not completely satisfied with myself yet,
止まらず、今に安堵せず進んでいくぞっていう
but I'll keep going without stopping or complacency.
「IN PROGRESS」っていうタイトルにしました！
That's why I chose the title "IN PROGRESS"!
はぁー、ま、ちょっと駆け足で紹介しましたが
Phew... well, I've introduced it a bit hurriedly,
奏、ちょっとお水飲んでいきたいので
but I'd like to go and get some water,
ダンサーさんたち、場を繋いでもらえますか？
so Dancers, could you keep the stage going for a bit?
無理ー
Impossible!
無理じゃない！やるんだよ！
It's not impossible! You have to do it!
はい、お願いします！
Yes, please!
面白い動きとかいっぱいお願いします！
Please do lots of interesting movements!
何の動きですか？
What kind of movement is that?
内緒ー！
It's a secret!
パワハラ奏みたいになっちゃいましたが
It ended up looking like Power Harassment Kanade,
普段、奏のダンスの指導をしている
but they are actually my dance instructors
とっても親しい先生たちですよ、ね？
who guide me. We're very close, right?
はい！
Yes!
言わせたみたいな...
It sounds like I forced you...
今日の意気込み、なんか
Could you tell us your enthusiasm for today,
「うおー！」とかで言ってもらえますか？
maybe with a "Woooo!" or something?
頑張りまーす！
We'll do our best!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ダンサーさんたちもありがとうございます。
Thank you so much, Dancers.
ではではでは、
Now, now, now...
次はゲストパートになります。
it's time for the guest part.
最初はいったい誰かな？
I wonder who's first?
楽しみということで、じゃあ、
I'm looking forward to it. So,
早速次の曲行きましょう！
let's get straight to the next song!
Party is over
それでも踊りたかった
I still wanted to dance
眠れないくらい 情熱の火はいつしか
Before I knew it, the fire of passion...
眠れないくらい
to the point I couldn't even sleep.
いつの日かに はなから気付いている
I've noticed from the start, that someday...
焔はいつか消える ねぇ
The flame will eventually go out, won't it?
なにも要らないはずだった なのにまだ I'm so serious
I shouldn't have needed anything, yet I'm still so serious
ああまだ間に合う
Ah, it's still not too late
ああただ Burn it up Baby
Ah, just burn it up baby
Sorry darling そんなに甘くないよ
Sorry darling, it's not that sweet
でもきっとそんなに悪くないよ
But I'm sure it's not that bad
Give me fire Light it up Baby
燃やしちゃうぜyeah
I'm gonna burn it up, yeah
燃えろよ燃えろよ 炎よ燃えろ
Burn on, burn on, oh flame, burn on
やぁ!千代も八千代
Hey! Through the ages
変わりもせずに
Without changing
ひとのなり いとをかし 全部燃やせ
Human form, how delightful, burn it all
出でよ舞えよ火の粉
Come out and dance, sparks
焚き付けるのが仕事
It's my job to kindle them
ガソリンとステロイド
Gasoline and steroids
燃えるさまはお見事
The way it burns is magnificent
火遊びはしない
I won't play with fire
ぬるいまね出来ない
I can't do lukewarm things
しけたカルマトラウマ燃やし尽くすマグマドラマ
Magma drama burning up damp karma and trauma
この飽くなき渇き 青い炎みたい
This insatiable thirst, like a blue flame
死は過去のひとつ隣 やがて総てひとつとなり
Death is right next to the past, all becomes one
Love is dying でもまだ消えてないから
Love is dying, but it hasn't disappeared yet
忘れてみたい 情熱の火はいつしか
I want to try to forget, the fire of passion...
いつの日かに 身体は気付いている
Someday, my body notices
僕らはいつか消える
that we will disappear someday
ゆるやかに若さを溶かして
Slowly melting youth away
泣かないで Why so serious？
Don't cry, why so serious?
ああまだ間に合う
Ah, it's still not too late
ああただ Burn it up Baby
Ah, just burn it up baby
Sorry darling そんなに甘くないよ
Sorry darling, it's not that sweet
でもきっとそんなに悪くないよ
But I'm sure it's not that bad
Give me fire Light it up Baby
燃やしちゃうぜyeah
I'm gonna burn it up, yeah
Turn it up, turn it up, turn it up!
足りない 注ぐ火に油
Not enough! Pouring oil on the fire!
Sorry darling Hurry up
ああ まだ間に合う
Ah, still in time
Sorry darling Hurry up
ああ ただ burn it up
Ah, just burn it up
Give me fire
Light it up Baby
燃やしちゃうぜ yeah
I'll burn it up, yeah
Party is over
それでも踊りたかった
Still, I wanted to dance
お誕生日おめでとう！ Happy Birthday!
Happy birthday! Happy Birthday!
Thank you very much!
おめでとう！ 奏ちゃん！
Congratulations! Kanade-chan!
Thank you! Birthday Girl!
まず最初のゲストは、カリオペ先輩に来てもらいました！
Our very first guest, Calliope-senpai is here!
はじめまして！ Hi everybody, yo yo, what's up?
Nice to meet you! Hi everybody, yo yo, what's up?
It's Mori Calliope here today to celebrate Kanade's special birthday y'all!
奏の誕生日祝いに来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to celebrate my birthday!
いえいえ。めっちゃ緊張してった。
Not at all. I was so nervous.
ラップする前、「やばい、できない、できない」と思ってた。
Before the rap, I was thinking, 'Oh no, I can't do this, I can't do this.'
いえいえ！めちゃくちゃ感じなかったですよ、そんな。
No way! I didn't get that feeling from you at all.
難しい日本語のラップ...
A difficult Japanese rap...
頑張りました！
I did my best!
かっこよかったです！もうなんか...
You were so cool! It was just...
奏ちゃんもかっこよかったよ。
You were cool too, Kanade-chan.
え、嬉しい！一緒にいい感じになりました。イェーイ！
Oh, I'm so happy! We had a great vibe together. Yay!
一緒に歌いたかったんですよ。
I've always wanted to sing with you.
私も！
Me too!
カリオペ先輩のラップが大好きで、「Beyond the Way」でも実をご一緒させていただいたりしましたから、それ以来じゃないか？
I love Calliope-senpai's rap so much... we collaborated in 'Beyond the Way,' so isn't this the first time since then?
そうですね、あんまり、うん、機会がなくて。
That's true, we haven't had many opportunities.
でも、でも今回すごかった！
But, but this time was amazing!
わあ、嬉しい！ぶちかましました！
Wow, I'm so happy! We really brought the house down!
ぶちかましました！
We really did!
それかっこいい！奏もやりたいけど、今息切れてるからできないよ。
That's so cool! I want to do it too, but I'm out of breath right now.
No no no, スタミナ、スタミナ守って。
No no no, save your stamina, save your stamina.
はい、先輩ありがとうございます。スタミナ。
Yes, thank you senpai. Stamina.
水たくさん飲んで。
Drink lots of water.
はい。お水飲みに行ってこようかな。
Yes. I think I'll go get some water.
Go go go! Yes, yes, yes!
Hi everybody! 奏ちゃん水タイム、what's up? I'm Mori Calliope.
Hi everybody! It's Kanade-chan's water time, what's up? I'm Mori Calliope.
アブラー！
Abura!
できた！
I did it!
アブラー！ちょっと忘れちゃうと思ってたけど、できた！
Abura! I thought I might forget it for a second, but I did it!
生歌すごい好きだから、今回誘ってくれてありがとうございます。
I love live singing so much, so thank you for inviting me this time.
こちらこそありがとうございます、本当に。一緒に歌えてすごく光栄でした。
Thank you too, really. It was such an honor to sing together.
またやろう！
Let's do it again!
ぜひ！ご一緒させてください。
Definitely! Please let me join you again.
お願いします。
Looking forward to it.
ということで、カリオペ先輩ありがとうございました！
And with that, thank you very much, Calliope-senpai!
ありがとうございました！これから頑張ってね。Good luck!
Thank you! Good luck with the rest of the show!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
You can do it!
Thank you very much!
Peace! Bye bye!
Bye bye!
ふう... ということで、カリオペ先輩との「火炎」でした。
Whew... And that was 'Kaen' with Calliope-senpai.
次の曲行く前に、ちょっと暑いから、ちょっと着替えてきてもいいですか？
Before the next song, it's a bit hot, so can I go change really quick?
ちょっと待っててくださいね。
Please wait just a moment.
ふう... ちょっとジャケット脱いできました。
Whew... I took off my jacket.
ちょっと熱気がもうすごい。
The heat is just incredible.
お前らもいっぱい、かっけー、ありがとう。ありがとうございます。
You guys too, so many 'cool' comments, thank you. Thank you so much.
コメント見てるよ。
I'm reading the comments.
では早速、次の曲行きましょうかね。
Now then, let's move on to the next song.
ゲスト誰か楽しみですね。
I wonder who the guest is, how exciting.
では、聞いてください。
Well then, please listen.
語れない 眠れない とろいメロウ
Can't tell, can't sleep, slippery mystery
あなたの見てるショーは 誰にも読めない
The show you're watching, no one can read
カルテ 昔々知りたいだけ
The medical chart, I just want to know the olden days
不可思議のカルテ
[Title: Fukashigi no Karte]
嘘も 現実も どっちも
Whether lies or reality, both
真実だったの 本当よ
Were the truth, it's true
今日も ひとりごと
Today as well, talking to myself
何にも 無理をしないで
Don't push yourself at all
わたし 愛されたい
I want to be loved
うやむや さよなら 軽いめまい
Indistinctly, goodbye, a slight dizziness
あなたのいない 結晶界
A crystalline world without you
誰も読めない
No one can read
...カルテ
...medical chart.
自意識 溢れ出して
Self-consciousness overflowing,
鼓動 世界像
heartbeat, world view.
いつも噛み合わないの
They never match,
痛くて
it hurts.
毎夜ねがいごと
Every night, a wish.
なんにも疑わないで
Don't doubt anything,
混ざり融け合いたい
I want to melt together.
たわいない 判らない
Frivolous, I don't know,
理由 存在
reason, existence.
あなたと残す後悔
The regret I leave with you.
誰も読めないカルテ
A medical chart no one can read.
不愉快 繰り返して
Unpleasant, repeating...
正しい夢は
Are correct dreams,
かなしい声は
sad voices,
美しい? 疑わしい?
beautiful? Suspicious?
羨ましい?
Are you envious?
ねえ、どれ?
Hey, which one?
語れない 眠れない トロイメライ
Can't speak, can't sleep, Traumerei.
あなたの見てる正体
The true form you're looking at.
誰も読めないカルテ
A medical chart no one can read.
不可思議 知りたいだけ
I just want to know the mystery.
終わらないことはない
There is nothing that doesn't end,
トロイメライ
Traumerei.
あなたと跨ぐ境界
The boundary I cross with you.
誰も読めないカルテ
A medical chart no one can read.
思春期 疵口 胸のうち
Puberty, scar, inside the chest.
不可思議 知りたいだけ
I just want to know the mystery.
はい、ということで、にじさんじから
Alright, and so, we have
町田ちまさんに来ていただきました！
Machita Chima-san here from Nijisanji!
おまえらの皆さんこんばんは！上から読んでも
Good evening, everyone! Whether you read it
下から読んでも町田ちまです！
forwards or backwards, I'm Machita Chima!
うわーい！ちまさんにもおまえらが浸透してる！
Yay! "Omaera" has reached Chima-san too!
もちろん知っていますよ！
Of course I know it!
知ってるんですか！？
You know it?!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！そして！
Happy birthday! And also!
すごーい！めでたいめでたい！
Amazing! Congrats, congrats!
なんですか、その動き？やばい。
What is that movement? It's crazy.
いや、つい、やっちゃうんです。癖なんです。
No, I just... I end up doing it. It's a habit.
それちょっと、リハーサルの時もやってた。
You were doing that during the rehearsal too.
やめて、バラすのやめてください。
Stop, please don't expose me.
変な動きが出る方なんですね。
You're the type to make strange movements, I see.
うふふ。でも今日はちょっと大人しくね、お話します。
Hehe. But today I'll talk a bit more calmly.
なるほど。全然出してもらって大丈夫ですからね。
I see. It's totally fine to let it all out, though.
あの、そういえば先日、一緒に『空想列車』という
By the way, we recently collaborated on a cover
楽曲の歌ってみたをコラボさせていただきまして。
of the song "Kuso Ressha".
しました。ありがとうございました。
We did. Thank you very much.
こちらこそ、お誘いいただいて本当に嬉しかったです！
Same here, I was really happy you invited me!
そうですか！やったやった。
Is that so! Yay, yay.
ちまさんの透明な歌声に絶対に似合うだろうなと思って
I thought it would suit your clear voice perfectly,
『空想列車』も今回の曲も選曲させていただきました。
so I chose "Kuso Ressha" and this song as well.
嬉しい！一緒に歌えてとっても嬉しいです！
I'm happy! I'm so glad we could sing together!
奏も幸せです！
Kanade is happy too!
え、なんか一個気になってることがあって。
Um, also, there's one thing I'm curious about.
何でしょう？
What is it?
『空想列車』のコメント欄に、ちまさんのこと
In the comments of "Kuso Ressha," referring to you,
『化け物』って書いてあったんですけど、あれは何？
it said "monster"... What's up with that?
多分、違う人のこと言ってるのかなって思うので。
I think they're probably talking about someone else.
忘れてください。
Please forget about it.
わかりました。あ、そんな、こんな綺麗な、お姉さん...
Understood. Oh, wait, such a beautiful lady...
そうよ。化け物なわけないですよね。見間違いですよ。
That's right. No way she's a monster. It's a mistake.
我々二人とも清楚だもんね。
We're both pure and wholesome, after all.
ねえ？
Right?
もちろんです。清楚ですよ、そりゃあもう。
Of course. We're wholesome, obviously.
はい、ということで、一緒に歌えてとっても嬉しかったです！
Alright, so, I was so happy to sing with you!
こちらこそ、嬉しかった！
I was happy too!
よかったらまた、機会があったら一緒に歌わせてください。
If there's another chance, let's sing together again.
いつでも歌いましょう！
Let's sing anytime!
やったー！言質取りました！
Yay! I've got your word!
やったやった。嬉しい。
Yay, yay. I'm happy.
じゃあ、この後も引き続き頑張ってください！
Well then, keep doing your best for the rest!
ありがとうございます！またね！
Thank you! See you later!
またね！
See you!
ということで ちょっと奏もお水を飲んできてもいいですか？
So, can Kanade go get some water too?
ちょっとだけお水飲んできます
I'll go drink some water for a bit.
まだまだまだまだ続いていきますよ
It's still going on, and on, and on!
次は誰かしら あと二人ですね
I wonder who's next? There's two left.
二分の一の確率 それでは楽しみにしててください
A 50/50 chance. Please look forward to it.
次の曲 行くぞー！
Next song, here we go!
G4L
作詞：q*Left 作曲：Giga
[Title: G4L / Lyrics: q*Left / Composition: Giga]
あれがせいかいなんて
That's the reason
だれのなれのはて
Whose end is it
なんだってのもんもんもん
Everything is so vague
こたえもほしいのも
I want answers too
いっこてこれだけ
Just this much
なやんだって
Even if I worry
しょうがないじゃんね
It can't be helped
あれはゆめだったって
It was just a dream
おもうことにしたって
I tried to think that
つら
Pain
でもぜんぜんおもえないんだけど
But I can't feel it at all
たすけてよふぉろわー
Help me, follower
あらがうだけ
Just fighting
わかさにまけ
Losing to the young
Next, next
Lucky lucky and lucky!
あありいお
A, B, C
わりきれたらさ
If you can't decide
おおりいお
X, Y, Z
らくなのにとか
Even though it's easy
ああんん
Oh no
もうやだ
I'm done with this
なんというしんせかいか
What a mysterious world
あなたいがいは
I don't need anyone
あなたいがいはいらないないない
Except you, except you
はらないでよばりあ
Don't call me
あるはずなのなにか
There must be something
あったならば
If it existed
Happy! Jumpin’ yeah!
Happy! Jumpin' yeah!
あなたのそのてと
If your hand
あたしのこのてを
Holds mine
つないだらもうにどとはなさないわ
I won't let go again
あなたのそのてが
If your hand
あたしのこのてを
Grabs mine
つかんだら
I'll never let go
いごおみしりおきを！my love
I'll remember it! My love
これでおわりなんて
This can't be the end
あがれないままなんて
Can't just give up
ないちゃって ぽんぽんぽん
Don't disappear, pon pon pon
どうにかなっちゃえって ねがってねがって
Figure it out somehow, wishing, wishing
ねえ、あさがえりしたり しーちゃわん？どう
Hey, let's rise up. Shichuan? How
なあもうがまんできん
I can't take it anymore
Pain pain
いたいってば everyday
It hurts everyday
まゆうていけるけどな
I can endure it
ぶるべなつなんでかんけいないなねえ
But it doesn't matter
だれよりもねこ
I'm more stubborn than anyone
せっそうないもけっこう
I'm fine without a partner
あしはあしだ
Foot is foot
みといてよ ready
Watch closely, ready
もうきょうでおわらせたいなって
I want to finish it today
りすたーとできたらって
If I could restart
でもむりよ
But it's impossible
もう
No more
What’s on your mind?
What's on your mind?
あありいお
A, B, C
わりきれたらさ
If you can't decide
おおりいお
X, Y, Z
らくなのにとか
Even though it's easy
もうやだ
I'm done with this
なんというしんせかいか
What a mysterious world
あなたいがいは
I don't need anyone
あなたいがいはいらないないない
Except you, except you
はらないでよばりあ
Don't call me
あるはずなのなにか
There must be something
あったならば
If it existed
Happy! Jumpin’ yeah!
Happy! Jumpin' yeah!
あなたのそのてと
If your hand
あたしのこのてを
Holds mine
つないだらもうにどとはなさないわ
I won't let go again
あなたのそのてが
If your hand
あたしのこのてを
Grabs mine
つかんだら
I'll never let go
いごおみしりおきを！my love
I'll remember it! My love
ならな うーーーー
It won't change
おみしりおきを！my love
I'll remember it! My love
はい！なんと3人目のゲストは、同じく にじさんじから 戌亥とこさんに 来ていただきました！
Yes! And our third guest is Inui Toko-san, also from NIJISANJI!
まいどー！にじさんじ所属公式つよつよケルベロス戌亥とこです！
Maido! I'm NIJISANJI's official strongest Cerberus, Inui Toko!
戌亥とこです
I'm Inui Toko.
戌亥とこ
Inui Toko.
いー！
I-!
えー難しい
Eh, it's hard.
いいよ好きに呼んでいいですよ
It's okay, you can call me whatever you like.
戌亥とこさん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Inui Toko-san, happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
Happy Birthday!
Nice to meet you!
Nice to meet you too! はじめ...
Nice to meet you too! Nice to...
はじめましてじゃない
It's not "nice to meet you".
はじめましてですよ
It *is* nice to meet you.
今日初めて会いました
We met for the first time today.
今日ガチの初めまして
Today is a real "first time meeting".
いるの？今日ガチの初めまして、私たち
Is it? Today is really our first time meeting?
いないいないいない
No, no, no.
初めまして 初めまして
Nice to meet you. Nice to meet you.
ちょっとね ちまさんとは『空想列車』の『歌ってみた』でご一緒させていただいたんですけど
Well, I did a "Kuso Ressha" cover with Chima-san,
本当の本当の今日初めまして
But today is the real, real first meeting.
本当の初めまして はい
A real first meeting. Yes.
もう今日初めましての時
When we met for the first time today,
あの とこさんが楽屋に来ていただいて 挨拶に来ていただいて ありがとうございます
Um, Toko-san came to my dressing room to say hello. Thank you very much.
いえいえ こちらこそ
No, no, same here.
で、なんかその時にお弁当が奏の部屋にあったから
And, there was a bento in Kanade's room at that time,
あ、よかったらお弁当食べますか？って言って 選んでください
So I asked, "Oh, would you like to have a bento? Please choose one."
カレーだったんですけど、カレーとなんか付随するものがあるお弁当だったんで
It was curry, a bento with curry and some side dishes.
そうなんですけど、なんか...
That's true, but somehow...
トコさんが一言放ったんですよ
Toko-san said something.
「芋だ！」
"It's potatoes!"
お芋が大好きなんです、私
I really love potatoes.
芋？ お芋めっちゃ好きなんですよ
Potatoes? I really like potatoes.
カレーなのにお芋？
Even though it's curry, you want potatoes?
お芋が好きやから
Because I like potatoes.
芋好きなんだって思って、芋があるお弁当だったから
I thought, "You like potatoes," and since it was a bento with potatoes...
ああ、よかったと思って、じゃあちょっと芋一番大きいの選びますねって言って
"Oh, good," I thought. So I said, "I'll pick the biggest potato for you."
奏チョイスでね
Kanade's choice.
選んで、別にそれをこうあげようとしたわけじゃないんですけど
I picked it, not that I was necessarily going to give it to her...
トコさんが採用してくださって
...but Toko-san accepted it.
いや、それはするでしょ
Well, of course I would.
そんなだだってせっかくこれ一番お芋大きいですって選んでくれたら
Since you went to the trouble of picking the biggest one for me...
「じゃあこれ！」って
...I'm like, "Then I'll take this one!"
「かしこまりました」って
"Certainly," I said.
めちゃくちゃ嬉しかったです、あれ
I was so happy about that.
なんか色んな味あったんですけど、お芋の大きさだけで選んでましたよね
There were various flavors, but I was choosing just by the size of the potato.
違うよ、奏が選んでくれたから持っていったんよ、私は
No, it's because Kanade picked it for me that I took it.
感動しました
I was so moved.
あ、そうなんですか？
Oh, really?
大好き！
I love you!
ちょっとよかったら、あの、今後とも何か機会があったら
If you'd like, if there's any opportunity in the future...
もちろん！
Of course!
なんか一緒にやりましょう
...let's do something together.
いくらでもやろう、一緒に
Let's do as much as you want, together.
本当ですか？ ユニットも組みますか？
Really? Shall we form a unit?
もうなんでもやろう、全部やろう
Let's do anything, let's do it all.
本当ですか？ よっしゃ！ ユニット名、カルニェで
Really? Yes! The unit name will be 'Karunie'...
ちょっと被るか... ちょっと被るか
...it's a bit similar. It's a bit similar.
っていうのは冗談で、なんか一緒にできたら嬉しいです
Just kidding, but I'd be happy to do something together.
トコさん、ありがとうございました
Toko-san, thank you very much.
またね！
See you!
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!
ということでですね、次がゲストは最後になります
And so, the next guest will be the last.
最後はあの人って、みんなわかるよね？
The last guest is that person... you all know who it is, right?
楽しみにしててくださーい！
Please look forward to it!
それでは、次の曲行きます
Now, let's go to the next song.
浪漫と算盤
作詞・作曲: 椎名林檎
[Title: Roman to Soroban / Lyrics & Music: Shiina Ringo]
主義を以って利益を成した場合は
If you make a profit through a principle
商いが食い扶持以上の意味を宿す
Business means something more than a means of earning a livelihood
義務と権利双方重んじつつ飽く迄
Considering duties and rights important, but I don't want to give priority to either of them
両者割合は有耶無耶にしていたい
I'd like to keep the ratio of the two ambiguous
玄人衆素人衆皆の衆賛否両論頂戴
Pros and amateurs alike, please give me your opinions
置きに行こうなんぞ野暮
It's tasteless to play it safe
新しい技毎度練り出したいです
I want to try something new on every occasion
苦しくとも僕には判っている
Even if it's painful, I know...
貴方も同じ様にひとり生きている
...that you live alone just the same as I do.
宇宙を因数分解したとこで自由と
Even if you factorize the universe...
孤独だけが待っているんでしょう
...only freedom and loneliness are waiting, aren't they?
玄人で素人で労働者で生活者の侭
As a pro, an amateur, a worker, and a liver...
面白可笑しく居させて
...let me stay here happily and funnily.
煩わしい役毎度請け負いたいです
I want to take on annoying roles every time.
虚しくとも
Even if it's empty...
貴方を思うたび
...whenever I think of you,
僕は赦されていく
I am forgiven.
夢と現を結わえて
Tying together dreams and reality.
浪漫と算盤
[Title: Romanticism and the Abacus]
屹度そう浪漫抱えたら算盤弾いて
I'm sure if you hold onto romance, play with the abacus
両極のど真ん中狙い撃って
Aim right at the middle of both extremes
お願い勇気をおくれ・・
Please give me courage...
疑わしい相手なら
If it's a suspicious partner
いつだって
Always
自分ずっと進化したいよね
I want to keep evolving
答え合わせ貴方を知るほど
Checking the answers, the more I know you
僕は正されていく
I am corrected
捨てた物じゃないただ生きようと
It's not something to throw away, I'll just live
うわー！
Whoa—!
マイクが遠いぜ
The mic is so far away.
体震えた！
My body was shaking!
なんてタフな持ち方
What a tough way to hold it.
ロッカーでしょ？
You're a rocker, right?
イェーイ！
Yeah!
いやいいですね。スタンドマイクかっこいいじゃないですか。
Well, that was great.
The mic stands look cool, don't they?
かっこいいですよね！
They are cool, aren't they?
ね。おめでとうございます、本当に。
Yeah. Congratulations, really.
あ、ありがとうございます！
Ah, thank you so much!
ひょっ。これちょっと受けるの。
Whoops. This is a bit funny.
もう一回いこう。せーの。
Let's do it again. Ready, set...
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
はい、ということで。
最後のゲストは、すいちゃん先輩でした！
Yes, and so... our final guest
was Suichan-senpai!
はい！ありがとうございます、呼んでくださって。
Yes! Thank you very much for inviting me.
彗星の如く現れたスターの原石！バーチャルアイドルの星街すいせいです！皆さんこんにちはー！
It's the star's diamond in the rough! Virtual idol
Hoshimachi Suisei! Hello, everyone!
こんにちはー！かわいい！
Hello! So cute!
はい。音の瀬の皆さんなんですよね。
Yes. You're the "Otonose" fans, right?
あ、はい！そうです。正式名称。
Ah, yes! That's right. The official name.
素晴らしい。ね、音の瀬の皆さんいつも
「お前ら」と言われていますけれども。
Wonderful. You "Otonose" fans are always
being called "you guys"...
はい。
Yes.
いやもう、今回の「浪漫と算盤」という楽曲。
Well, this song, "Roman to Soroban"...
すいちゃん先輩と一緒に歌ったら
絶対にカッコいいだろうって思って。
I thought it would definitely be cool
if I sang it with Suichan-senpai.
まあカッコいいけどさ。
生でやるもんじゃないよね。
Well, it is cool, but...
it's not something you should do live, right?
もう私、本当にさ。私、昨日とかさ。
I mean, really. Yesterday and all...
「歌える、歌える、歌えるかしら？」って。
もうね、すごい不安だったけど。
"Can I sing it? Can I really sing it?"
I was so worried.
今日合わせてみて。良かったじゃん。
But we tried it today, and it was great.
良かったですよ！めちゃくちゃ美声でしたよ。
It was great! Your voice was incredibly beautiful.
めちゃめちゃ美声でしたよ返し。
An "incredibly beautiful voice" right back at you.
え、ありがとうございます！
Eh, thank you!
え、嬉しい。ね、コメント欄もね。
Oh, I'm so happy. Look at the comments too.
うん。え、めっちゃ良かった。うん。めちゃめちゃ相性良かった。
Yeah. It was so good. Yeah.
Our chemistry was amazing.
ほら、相性良かったって。
See, they're saying we had great chemistry.
嬉しい！よかったらまた歌ってくださいよ、一緒に。
I'm so glad! If you'd like,
please sing with me again.
え、そうそう。なんか二人だけで歌うのは初めてなんだよね。
Oh, right. It's actually the first time
just the two of us have sung together.
そうなんです。「パンダヒーロー」でなんか
四人で一緒に歌うっていうことはあったんですけど。
That's right. We sang "Panda Hero"
together as a group of four before...
今回二人きりは初めてということで。
But this time, it's the first time
with just the two of us.
ねえ、すごい楽しかったですし。またね、呼んでくださいよ。奏ちゃん。
Yeah, it was so much fun.
Please invite me again, Kanade-chan.
かなまちょのためなら、駆けつけますよ。
For Kanamacho's sake, I'll come running.
生でハモリという、すごい難しい難題を
一緒に飛び越えられて嬉しい。
I'm so happy we could overcome the difficult
challenge of harmonizing live together.
飛び越えたね！
We sure did!
嬉しかったね！頑張りました、私たち。
It was so happy! We worked hard.
是非とも、あのアーカイブも残るしね、
何回も聴き返してほしいですね。
By all means, since the archive will be saved,
I want everyone to listen back many times.
はい、是非！
Yes, please!
ということで、奏さん、この後も
まだまだ続くと思いますけれども。頑張ってください。
And so, Kanade-san, I think there's still
more to come, so... Good luck.
ありがとうございます！本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you! Thank you so much!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you!
それでは、失礼します。
With that, I'll take my leave.
はい！ありがとうございましたー！
Yes! Thank you very much!
さあ、ゲストの皆さんにね、たくさん
盛り上げていただきましたということで。
Now then, our guests have
really helped liven things up.
こっからはソロでですね、頑張っていきますよ。
From here on, I'll be
doing my best solo.
ということで。まだまだまだまだ盛り上げていきます。
So, I'm going to keep things exciting.
その前にちょっと、準備とお水を飲んでくるので、
待っててください。
But before that, I'm going to get ready and
drink some water, so please wait a moment.
行ってきまーす！
I'm off!
こっからは、一気に5曲、いっちゃいます！
From here on, I'm going to do
five songs in a row!
次は...
Next is...
最後には...
At the end...
し、し、し、シークレットだもん！
It-It-It-It's a secret!
最後のお楽しみ、ということで。
So, look forward to that at the end.
それでは次の曲、聴いてください。
Now then, please listen to the next song.
All Alone With You.
All Alone With You / 作詞・作曲: ryo (supercell)
[All Alone With You / Music & Lyrics: ryo (supercell)]
誰かを愛することなんて
Loving someone...
できるわけなくって
...is something I could never do,
だけど誰かに愛されたくて
but I still want to be loved by someone.
変わらない昨日がずっと続いたとしても
Even if the unchangeable yesterday continues forever,
どこにも行けやしないんだ
I can't go anywhere.
私とキミ
You and I.
神さま どこへ行ってしまったの ねえ
God, where did you go? Hey...
返事はなくて
There's no reply,
いつだってそうだよ
it's always like that.
Are you still here?
You'll never walk alone
あなたと行く
I'll go with you.
どんな罪も
Whatever sins you have,
背負ってあげる
I'll bear them for you.
道なき道を
Down the pathless road,
歩いてくの
I'll keep walking,
あなたと二人で
just the two of us.
こっちにきて
Come here.
私に触れて キスをして
Touch me, kiss me.
もっとめちゃくちゃに
Would you make it...
したっていいんだよ?
...even more chaotic?
いつか誰もが死んじゃって
If someday everyone dies
忘れられてくなら
and gets forgotten,
今確かなものだけを信じるわ
I'll only believe in what's certain now.
神さま気取りの人が言うの
People who act like God say,
ねえ 人は強いって
"Hey, people are strong."
そんなの嘘だよ
That's a lie.
Do you agree?
I will stay with you
あなたの手で
With your hands,
抱きしめてよ
hold me tight
思いっきり
with all your might.
怖がらないで
Don't be afraid.
もう大丈夫 私なら
It's alright, if it's me.
その手が汚れて
Even if those hands
しまったとしても
have become dirty,
愛してほしい
I want you to love...
私のこと
...me.
You'll never walk alone
あなたと行く
I'll go with you.
どんな罪も
Whatever sins you have,
背負ってあげる
I'll bear them for you.
道なき道を
Down the pathless road,
歩いてくの
I'll keep walking,
あなたと
with you.
I will stay with you
あなたの手で
With your hands...
All Alone With You
[Song: All Alone With You]
抱きしめて
Hold me...
思い切り 望めないものならば
...if it is something I cannot wish for with all my heart,
何もないから
since there is nothing,
あなたと
I want to be with you...
二人で
...just the two of us.
give it back
[Song: give it back]
あたたかい涙で
With warm tears...
ふいに目覚めた
...I suddenly woke up.
焦がれた夢の
Where is the continuation...
続きはどこにあるの
...of the dream I longed for?
寂しいよ
I'm lonely.
please, give it back
いつになれば楽になれる
When will it be easier?
押しては返す 波に抗がって
Resisting the waves that push and return...
白い枕に
In the white pillow...
寝ぼけたままの顔を 埋めて
...I bury my sleepy face.
同じ夢を 願うほどに増えていくよ
The more I wish for the same dream, the more it grows.
please, give it back
代わりなんていないよ
There's no replacement.
あなたの匂い 思い出せない波にさらって
Carried away by the waves that I can't remember your scent.
夢の続きを 掴みに行くから待ってて
I'll go grab the continuation of the dream, so wait for me.
いつの間にか 届く頃には
Without me noticing, by the time it reaches me,
優しさに触れ過ぎた
I've touched too much kindness.
湿ってく顔上げてみようか
Shall I try lifting my wet face?
ひとりじゃないって
That I'm not alone...
信じてみたい 信じてみたいの
...I want to believe, I want to believe it.
give it a shot
生まれたばかりの 淡い光に
In the faint light just born...
希望を見たの 胸が熱いよ
...I saw hope, and my heart is warm.
手を握っていよう 迷わないように
Let's hold hands, so we won't lose our way...
明日からまた 選んだ道を進めるように
...so we can continue on the chosen path from tomorrow.
敗北の少年
[Title: Defeated Boy]
お前ら！まだまだいくぞー！
Everyone! We're still going!
ぶつかって
Bumping into things,
逃げ込んで
running away,
僕はいつしか ここに立ってた
before I knew it, I was standing here.
誰もが憧れる
I wanted to be a hero
ヒーローになりたくて でもなれなくて
that everyone admires, but I couldn't.
これぐらいじゃ
Even though I knew
届かないこと 分かっていたのに
that this wouldn't be enough to reach...
敗北の少年 現実を謳え
Defeated boy, sing of reality.
あんな風に空は飛べやしないんだ
We can't fly in the sky like that.
こんな夜に 意味があるなら
If there's meaning in a night like this,
僕らは地を這う
we crawl along the ground.
耳鳴りが こだまして
The ringing in my ears echoes,
僕に奇跡が 問いかけるんだ
and a miracle asks me.
「君の夢 憧れたヒーローに
"I'll make you the hero
今すぐ させてあげよう」
you've always dreamed of being right now."
飴みたいに 差し伸べられたって
Even if it's offered to me like candy,
嬉しくないんだ
I'm not happy about it.
敗北の少年 存在を謳え
Defeated boy, sing of your existence.
君みたいに眩しくはなれないけど
I can't be as dazzling as you,
こんな夜に 意味があるなら
but if there's meaning in a night like this,
僕らは地を這う
we crawl along the ground,
まだ地を這う
we still crawl along the ground.
鼓動を知って 息を吸い込んで
Feeling my heartbeat, taking a deep breath,
「僕は遠慮するよ」
"I'll pass on that."
敗北の...
Defeated...
敗北の少年 平凡を謳え
Defeated boy, sing of the ordinary.
あいにくと 神は信じないタチで
Unfortunately, I don't believe in God.
すれ違いの 物語よ さよなら
Goodbye to this story of passing each other by.
敗北の少年 現実を謳え
Defeated boy, sing of reality.
僕らは泥を 這い蹲るもの
We are the ones who grovel in the mud.
こんな夜も 愛しいから
Because even a night like this is precious,
僕らは地を這う
we crawl along the ground,
ただ地を這う
we just crawl along the ground.
あのね。
Hey...
Luna say maybe
[Title: Luna say maybe]
あのね。I say “私、大丈夫？”
You know, I say "Am I okay?"
Maybe, うまくやれるはず
Maybe I can pull it off.
ずっと走った息継ぎもしないまま
I've been running without catching my breath.
あっそう、終わりが来るなら別に寂しくなんかはない
Oh right, if the end comes, I won't be lonely.
真実は心の奥の方自分のことすら愛せないまま
Deep down, I still can't even love myself.
君のこと守れるのかな“信じて”
I wonder if I can protect you... "Believe me."
自分のことすら愛せないまま
Unable to even love myself,
君のこと守れるのかな
can I really protect you?
“信じて”
"Believe me."
どうか、正真正銘のこの思いを聴いて
Please, listen to these genuine feelings of mine.
私、全身全霊で歌うから
I'll sing with my whole heart and soul.
大丈夫、世界はこんなに綺麗だと、
It's okay, I know the world is this beautiful,
分かってる、分かってる、解ってる…
I know, I know, I understand...
わかってるよ！
I understand!
ごめんね。
I'm sorry.
じれったい
It's frustrating.
足りない、こんなんじゃ誰も愛せないの
It's not enough, I can't love anyone like this.
止めない、
I won't stop,
止まることは知らないの
I don't know how to stop.
言葉足らず、
Lacking the words,
失くしてしまう物ばかりだ
all I do is keep losing things.
Luna say maybe…
Luna say maybe...
降るのは、迷be, rainy
What's falling is maybe, rainy.
愛せ、どんな自分でも
Love yourself, no matter who you are.
Navy色に染まるまで
Until everything is dyed in Navy.
時間は
It might take
かかるかもしれないけど
some time, but...
I know, 輝くしかないこと
I know, I have no choice but to shine.
ハイライト、塗り続けるしかない
I have no choice but to keep painting the highlights.
真実はちゃんと、
The truth is something
言わなくちゃね
I have to say properly.
目に見えるものが続くと、ずっと
If visible things continue, forever,
そう、ずっと思いたい
yes, that's what I want to keep believing.
君に、半信半疑な素振りして
Showing you a half-doubting attitude,
心、空回り、遠回り
my heart spins in place, taking detours.
最低だ、もう一回やり直せるのなら
It's the worst; if I could start over one more time,
素直になりたい、なりたい、なりたいと
I want to be honest, I want to, I want to,
願ったジレンマ
I wished for in this dilemma.
このまま、1人じゃ何もできない
As I am, I can't do anything alone.
全部、決めるのは、自分次第
Everything depends on me to decide.
初めて背中をみた時に、覚悟を決めた。
When I first saw your back, I made up my mind.
どこまでいけるのか
How far I can go,
届くのか
whether I can reach you,
わからないよ
I just don't know.
臆病がそこに立っている
Cowardice is standing right there.
3秒前バックステージ
Three seconds before, backstage,
震える背中を君に預けて
I entrust my trembling back to you.
この運命的出会いはきっと、
This fateful encounter must surely,
そう、きっと
yes, surely...
偶然みたいな 多分、神様のいたずらです。
be like a coincidence, perhaps a prank by God.
どうか、正心正銘のこの思いが
Please, let these genuine feelings
君の心(ところ)にちゃんと届くまで
reach your heart properly.
ここで、私、全心全霊で歌うから
Until then, I'll sing here with all my heart and soul.
待ってる、待っている
I'm waiting, I'm waiting,
だから、この場所を大切にしたいの！
so I want to cherish this place!
これが、正真正銘の私だ！
This is the genuine me!
大丈夫、もう怖くはないわ
It's okay, I'm not afraid anymore.
たまにつまづくことなら、あるけれど
I might stumble sometimes, but...
1番特特席で君の笑顔見たいんだ
I want to see your smile from the best seat of all.
私だけの特権
That's my exclusive privilege.
見えない未来、手探り今日も
Groping through an unseen future, today too,
ステージの上で証明して見せるから
I'll prove it to you on this stage.
ここにしかないスクリーン
A screen that exists only here,
really！ re@lly！
really! re@lly!
君にまだ話せてないことばっかりあるんだ
There are so many things I haven't told you yet.
聴いて欲しいの
I want you to listen.
あのね、
You know...
今日は見に来てくれて本当にありがとう。
Thank you so much for coming to see me today.
最後は新曲をお届けします。
For the last part, I'll be performing a new song.
聴いてください。
Please listen.
You & 合図
You & Signal
目覚めの合図
The signal of awakening,
スマホが踊る
my smartphone dances.
そして半分眠った瞳で
And with half-asleep eyes,
心の震えは A=440Hz
my heart's trembling is A=440Hz.
今日のリズムは合言葉で合わせよう
Let's sync today's rhythm with a password.
ドゥルドゥル ドゥルドゥルドゥル
Dur-dur, dur-dur-dur.
一歩前に
One step forward,
レガート深呼吸
a legato deep breath.
会う前には二度の瞬き
Blinking twice before we meet.
月曜の約束を奏でよう
Let's play out our Monday promise.
ねえ、君と僕の合図
Hey, the signal between you and me.
Hey, the signal between you and me
もう一歩を 踏み出して
Take one more step
踏み出して 合わせてみよう
Take one more step, let's match it up
なんでマンデー どうしてサンデー
Why is it Monday? Why is it Sunday?
明日へ弾んでいたいの
I want to keep springing towards tomorrow
タクトをシュシュ ハッチをパンパン
Baton swish, handclaps bam-bam
ここからはすべてダ・カーポ
From here on, it's all da capo
日曜日のコーダを飛び越えて
Leaping over the coda of Sunday
待ってるよ 明日よ 来ないでと願ってしまうほど
I'm waiting, wishing for tomorrow not to come...
La La La...
あなたを待ちわびる 時間すらも愛おしい
Even the time waiting for you is dear to me
一歩前に レガート深呼吸
One step forward, a legato deep breath
スタッカートで二度の瞬き
With a staccato, two blinks
月曜の約束を奏でよう
Let's play the promise of Monday
ねえ、君と僕の合図
Hey, the signal between you and me
奏でよう ね、叶うよ
Let's play, yeah, it will come true
私たちだけの合図
The signal just for us
なんと！最後の曲は奏自身の2作目のオリ曲、『You & 合図』でした！
And! The final song was my second original song, 'You & 合図'!
パフパフ〜！
Pah-pah!
見て、可愛いでしょ、新曲のジャケ写です！
Look, it's cute right? Here's the jacket art for the new song!
[21日 00:00〜 リリース / MVはこのあとYouTubeでプレミア公開]
[Release: 21st 00:00 / MV Premiere on YouTube after this]
このあと24時、えーと21日の0時... 0時0時、ちょっと噛んじゃいました。
At 24:00 today... wait, 0:00 on the 21st... I tripped over my words.
21日の0時から配信開始です！
Distribution starts at 0:00 on the 21st!
もうね、すごく可愛い振り付けとなっているので、よかったら踊ってみてね！
The choreography is so cute, so please try dancing to it!
さらにこの配信のあとMVも、えーと21時10分からプレミア公開されます！
Furthermore, the MV will also premiere at 21:10 after this stream!
もうこちらの楽曲ですね、あの歌詞もちらっと見えていたから...
Regarding this track, since the lyrics were visible for a bit...
ちょっと気づいてるお前らもね、たくさんコメント欄でワクワクしていたと思うんですが、
I'm sure many of you noticed and were getting excited in the chat,
あの月曜日だったり、奏の要素がいっぱい込められている楽曲なので、いっぱい聴いてください。
it's a song filled with 'Monday' and other elements of me, so please listen to it a lot.
ということで皆さん、お待ちかねのグッズ情報も行って参りたいと思います！
With that, let's move on to the merchandise info you've been waiting for!
こちら！奏生誕記念グッズ2026！ パフパフパフ！ 可愛い！
Here it is! Kanade Birthday Celebration Goods 2026! Pah-pah-pah! So cute!
販売開始はこのあと21時20分からだから、安心して最後まで見ていてね。紹介していきます！
Sales start at 21:20 after this, so relax and watch until the end. Let's take a look!
まずは、こちら！ 奏と待ち合わせポストカードフレーム！
First up! 'Meeting up with Kanade' Postcard Frame!
今回のキービジュアルを『奏と待ち合わせ』をテーマに、ごむじママに書いていただきました。
Gomzi-mama drew this key visual with the theme 'Meeting up with Kanade'.
日常のワンシーンを飾るイメージで作ってみました。可愛いでしょ！
We made it with the idea of decorating a scene from daily life. Isn't it cute?
そのまま飾るほか、他のポストカードを挟んで別の絵柄で楽しむこともできます。
Besides displaying it as is, you can also swap in other postcards to enjoy it.
2つ目は、こちら！ また奏が落書きしちゃったw Tシャツ！
Second is this! 'Kanade Doodled Again lol' T-shirt!
奏の落書きTシャツ第2弾！ 本当に今日は月曜日！
The second in the Kanade Doodle T-shirt series! Today really is Monday!
もう月曜日盛りだくさんです。ハッピー月曜日！ ということで月曜日Tシャツです。
It's full of Monday. Happy Monday! So, it's the Monday T-shirt.
毎週月曜日にはこのTシャツを着て生活してください。最高、ありがとう！ 3つ目は...
Please wear this T-shirt every Monday. It's great, thank you! The third item is...
こちら！ 奏とおそろ！ネックレス！ 可愛いでしょ！
This! 'Matching with Kanade' Necklace! It's cute, right?
今回キービジュアルで私が付けているのとお揃いの、奏モチーフのネックレスです。
It's a Kanade-motif necklace, matching the one I'm wearing in the key visual.
確か私のデビュー日が書かれているはずです。よかったら！
I believe it has my debut date engraved on it. Check it out!
すごくシンプルでスタイリッシュなので、普段アクセを付けない人もぜひ付けてみてください。
It's very simple and stylish, so even if you don't usually wear accessories, please try it.
そして4つ目、こちら！ 「明日は月曜日!w」ひょっこりぬいぐるみ！
And the fourth item! 'Tomorrow is Monday! lol' Peeking Plushie!
いやーもうね、こちらの素敵なフリップを持った奏のぬいぐるみです。
Yes, it's a plushie of me holding this wonderful signboard.
画面モニターに引っ掛けて飾れるので、いつでも「月曜日だよ〜」ってお知らせいたします！
You can hang it on your monitor, and I'll always be there to tell you 'It's Monday!'
最後に、フルセット購入特典！ 数量限定で直筆サイン＆複製メッセージ入りポストカード！
Finally, the Full Set Purchase Bonus! A limited quantity postcard with a handwritten signature!
通常版は複製サイン入りポストカードとボイスが付いてきます。今回のボイスは...
The regular version comes with a printed signature postcard and a voice pack. This time...
いーよぉーっし！
Alright!
グッズ紹介！
Goods introduction!
お前らへの感謝とこれからの意気込みをありのまま伝えるフリートークボイスになっています。
It's a free talk voice recording where I share my gratitude and future enthusiasm.
ボイスはフルセットを購入したら必ず付いてくるから安心してね。
The voice recording is included with the full set, so don't worry.
以上、グッズ紹介でした！
That's all for the goods introduction!
みんな、今日は... 月曜日だね。
Everyone, today is... Monday.
そんな月曜日のお前らには... じゃーん！
For all of you on such a Monday... ta-dah!
今日は月曜日！犬！今回は犬です。
Today is Monday! Dog! It's a dog this time.
今日は月曜日ということで、犬のフリップ。
Since today is Monday, here's a dog flip-board.
今年ね、エイプリルフールネタを擦っていきますよ。ワン！
I'm going to keep using this year's April Fools' joke. Woof!
えっと、このあとメン限にてアンコールライブもやっちゃうよー！
Um, I'll be doing an encore live for members after this!
このQRコードは何なんだ？
What is this QR code?
アンコールではちょっとお前らのリクエストに答えたりするかも。うん、このQRあーあ...
I might take some requests during the encore. Yeah, this QR code, ah...
いけないいけない、お前ら読み込んでしまう。
Wait, wait, you guys will scan it.
このQRを読み込んだら、えっと、メンバーシップに入れるみたいです。
If you scan this QR, apparently you can join the membership.
うん、じゃあ見せないんでおっく、うぇーい、見せないんでおっく。
So I'll put it away, ueei, I won't show it.
え、見せちゃおうかな？どうしようかな？
Eh, should I show it? What should I do?
はい！えっと、それじゃあ...
Okay! Well then...
今日は本当に、あの、奏のライブに見に来てくれてありがとうございました。
Thank you all so much for coming to see Kanade's live performance today.
全編生ライブというすごい奏においても挑戦的なライブでして...
It was an entirely live performance, which was very challenging even for Kanade...
本当はめちゃくちゃ怖かったんですけど...
To be honest, I was really, really scared...
あの、なんとかなんとか、すごいポストXだったり、お前らがこう...
But somehow, thanks to all the posts on X and you guys...
応援のメッセージを送ってくれたおかげですごいな... もう緊張もそんなにせず終えられたかなと思います。
...sending me messages of support, I think I was able to finish without being that nervous.
本当に見に来てくれてありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for coming to see me!
それではメン限アンコールライブでまた会おうね！
Well then, let's meet again at the membership encore live!
ありがとう！またね！
Thank you! See you later!
チャンネル登録してね！
Please subscribe to the channel!